<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Engineering at Monsanto</title>
        <description>The engineers of Monsanto produce code that powers agricultural products that support farmers all around the world. Our goal of sustainable agriculture mirrors the way we present our ideas and code to the world.</description>
        <link>http://engineering.monsanto.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://engineering.monsanto.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
            <item>
                <title>Secret STDIN Slurper</title>
                
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/bash/&quot;&gt;BASH&lt;/a&gt; may be looked down upon by
all the programming language hipsters out there, but when you are
doing system-level tasks it can be quite convenient: it&amp;#39;s on every
system, it has no dependencies to install, and it can be a powerful
language when used properly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/27/secret-stdin-slurper/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/27/secret-stdin-slurper/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Modifying JSON on the command line</title>
                
                
                    <description>&lt;style scoped&gt;
  .projectKey { color: red }
  .map { color: orange }
  .plus { color: brown }
  .newValue { color: blue }
  .dot { color: hotpink }
  .toEntries { color: purple }
  .fromEntries { color: green }
&lt;/style&gt;
</description>
                
                <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/22/jq-change-json/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/22/jq-change-json/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Using Big Data for Good</title>
                
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading through blog posts, press releases, and source code you can easily get
the impression that everyone working in the Big Data space is focused on
determining what ads you are most likely to click.  From Facebook to Google to
Twitter, the modern players in IT collect massive amounts of information on
their customers and then analyze that data to provide ever more relevant ads.
As Jeff Hammeracher, formerly of Facebook and now with Cloudera, famously said,
&amp;ldquo;The best minds of my generation are thinking about how to make people click
ads.&amp;rdquo;  The result of this nearly singular focus is that many of the tools
developed to operate in the Big Data space aren&amp;#39;t easily applied to systems
that are much more complicated than counting words and providing links to ads.
As anyone who has tried to use NoSQL databases for complicated work flows on
distributed systems can tell you, pushing the limits of these systems that
eschew features for speed can be fraught with peril, forcing you to do a lot of
engineering on your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/20/using-big-data-for-good/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/20/using-big-data-for-good/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Learn implicits: Scala reflection</title>
                
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Implicits are arguably &lt;span class=&quot;banana&quot;&gt;the most&lt;/span&gt; unique and
misunderstood language feature of Scala.  Unlike other advanced features in the
language, they are very hard to avoid: most major libraries in Scala, starting
from Scala collections, make heavy use of implicits. That use is not invisible
to the users of the library, especially when we choose to look at the code. The
other tricky part about implicits is that there are so many ways to use them,
each with a different reason and pattern.  They can&amp;#39;t be fully explained in one
coherent post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/14/implicits-intro/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/05/14/implicits-intro/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>We are Monsanto Engineering</title>
                
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;At Monsanto, we are engineers: in our history we’ve engineered &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light-emitting_diode#Initial_commercial_development&quot;&gt;molecules&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AstroTurf&quot;&gt;materials&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L-DOPA&quot;&gt;medicines&lt;/a&gt;. Now as a purely agricultural company, we not only engineer plants, but the systems that develop, manufacture, monitor and deploy them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/04/06/we-are-monsanto-engineering/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/04/06/we-are-monsanto-engineering/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Stoop: our first open source release</title>
                
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to annouce the release of our first open source software, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MonsantoCo/stoop&quot;&gt;Stoop&lt;/a&gt;. Based on an existing &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackage.haskell.org/package/CouchDB&quot;&gt;Haskell library&lt;/a&gt;, Stoop is a Scala DSL for interfacing with CouchDB. Implementation can be easily switched between talking to an actual Couch or a fake (mock) one for testing. We&amp;#39;ve released this under the Modified BSD License, so check it out and let us know if you have any questions, if you find bugs, or even if you have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MonsantoCo/stoop/pulls&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; to fix something!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/04/05/stoop-our-first-open-source-release/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://engineering.monsanto.com/2015/04/05/stoop-our-first-open-source-release/</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
